const e="english",o=200,a=75,t=[{id:722,question:"b<u>oa</u>t?",option:{a:"board",b:"bought",c:"go",d:"glory"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTURE AND ORALFORMS</b> In each of the question 26 to 30 Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letters underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"boat; /bəʊt/                                                       go; /ɡəʊ/",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:26,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:723,question:`<u>Ai</u>r?


`,option:{a:"heir",b:"her",c:"hear",d:"fire"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTURE AND ORALFORMS</b> In each of the question 26 to 30 Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letters underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`<i>air and heir are both nouns with the same vowel sounds pronounced as  /ɛː/</i>

 `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:27,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:724,question:"Pl<u>ea</u>sure?",option:{a:"pliable",b:"pleat",c:" plenary",d:"jeopardy"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTURE AND ORALFORMS</b> In each of the question 26 to 30 Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letters underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:`pleasure is pronounced as [ˈplɛʒə], our area of emphasis is on the ''ea'' sound which goes thus ''ɛ''. As usual, i am going to give you the pronunciation of all the options above and the one with the same vowel sound as  depicted above, will be the correct answer.

pliable--- [ˈplʌɪəb(ə)l]

pleat----- [pliːt]

plenary-- [ˈpliːnəri]

jeopardy--- [ˈdʒɛpədi]. from the list of possible pronunciations above, you can see that only jeopardy [ˈdʒɛpədi] has the vowel sound ''ɛ'' and it is therefore the correct answer to the question.

 `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:28,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:725,question:`Thund<u>er</u>?
 `,option:{a:"prefer",b:"differ",c:"confer",d:"defer"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTURE AND ORALFORMS</b> In each of the question 26 to 30 Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letters underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:`Thunder |ˈθʌndə|
(a) prefer |prɪˈfɜː|
(b) differ  |ˈdɪfə| 
(c) confer  |kənˈfɜː| 
(d) defer |dɪˈfɜː|

 
`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:29,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:726,question:`T<u>ea</u>r?

. `,option:{a:"dare",b:"care",c:"here",d:"wear"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTURE AND ORALFORMS</b> In each of the question 26 to 30 Choose the option that has the same vowel sound as the one represented by the letters underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:`The verb tear is pronounced as /tɛː/

Wear is pronounced as /wɛː/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:30,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:727,question:"<u>Th</u>ought? ",option:{a:"theatre",b:"taught",c:"weather",d:"fate"},section:`<b>In each of the questions 31 to 32 choose from the options the word that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the underlined?</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Both thought and theater are pronounced alike with the tip of the tongue in between the front teeth. Hence we have;

thought1; /θɔːt/

theatre;​​​​​​​ /ˈθɪətə/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:31,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:728,question:"Cali<u>ph</u>? ",option:{a:"presently",b:"perhaps",c:"powerful",d:"opponent"},section:`<b>In each of the questions 31 to 32 choose from the options the word that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the underlined?</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`caliph; /ˈkeɪlɪf,ˈkalɪf/

powerful; /ˈpaʊəfʊl,ˈpaʊəf(ə)l/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:32,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:729,question:"ENORMOUS?",option:{a:"interest",b:"solution",c:"stupidly",d:"character"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 33 to 36 Select the word that has the same pattern of stress as the given word.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`The stress pattern of a word is the way all the syllables are stressed in it. There can be main and secondary stress, or unstressed sounds. 

The word SO-LU-TION has the same stress pattern as E-nor-mous as they are both stressed on the second syllable.

 `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:33,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:730,question:"HONOUR?",option:{a:"hotel",b:"hyena",c:"human",d:"humane"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 33 to 36 Select the word that has the same pattern of stress as the given word.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Honour is stressed as HO-nour.

same as HO-tel`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:34,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:731,question:"QUALITY?",option:{a:"guarantee",b:"accepted",c:"bachelor",d:"related"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 33 to 36 Select the word that has the same pattern of stress as the given word.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`Quality is stressed on the first syllable /ˈkwɒlɪti/

A. guarantee  is stressed on the third syllable /ɡar(ə)nˈtiː/

B. accepted  is stressed on the second syllable /əkˈsɛptid/

C. bachelor  is stressed on the first syllable /ˈbatʃələ/

D. related  is stressed on the second syllable /rɪˈleɪt/`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:35,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:732,question:"EDUCATION? ",option:{a:"duplicity",b:"economics",c:"elaborate",d:"conjectural"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 33 to 36 Select the word that has the same pattern of stress as the given word.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:36,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:733,question:"",option:{a:"reproduce",b:"always",c:"result",d:"understand"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 37 to 38 identify the word that has the stress on the second syllable.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`Bisyllabic verbs and prepositions are usually stressed on the second.

result is stressed on the second syllable as re-SULT`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:37,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:734,question:"",option:{a:"tomato",b:"photograph",c:"yesterday",d:"tranquil"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 37 to 38 identify the word that has the stress on the second syllable.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:38,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:735,question:"",option:{a:"integral",b:"intimate",c:"discourse",d:"accelerate"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 39 to 40 identify the word that has a different stress pattern from the others.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"All the other options except option D has its stress pattern on the first syllable.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:39,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:736,question:"",option:{a:"navigate ",b:"envelop",c:"legislate",d:"liberate"},section:"<b>In each of the questions 39 to 40 identify the word that has a different stress pattern from the others.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:40,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:737,question:"Without our relentless campaigns we might ....... sure of victory in the race for the National Assembly?",option:{a:"never have been",b:"have never be",c:" never had been",d:"be never"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"Option A contains a complete structural phrasal verb.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:41,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:738,question:"Weare all hungry; we……. anything to eatsincemorning.",option:{a:" didn’t have",b:"hadn’t had",c:"haven’t had",d:" never had"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:42,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:739,question:"To check desertification in the arid zones ...... tress should be planted?",option:{a:"drought-proof",b:"drought-resisting",c:" drought-effective",d:"drought-resistant"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:43,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:740,question:`The loquacious young lad reeled off all the names of 
the
players…….`,option:{a:" off head",b:"offhand",c:" at heart",d:"at hand"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:44,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:741,question:"I like the character that played the role of a political ....... at the last convention of our party?",option:{a:"thorncoat",b:"torncoat",c:"turncoat",d:"turnedcoat"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:45,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:742,question:`All the traders in the market saw thewoman buy... the 
imported suits.`,option:{a:"up",b:"off",c:"over",d:"out"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:46,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:743,question:"The man declared his intention from the -----",option:{a:"outset",b:"inset",c:"onset",d:"offset"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"onset simply means the beginning of something. in the statement above, it means the man made his intentions known from the beginning. option C best fits into the statement. ",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:47,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:744,question:"The team Manager told us that the race could only be won by the .......?",option:{a:"flat-footed",b:"bare-footed",c:"switf-footed",d:"fore-footed"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"To be swift-footed means  having rapidly moving feet or able to run very quickly",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:48,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:745,question:"The Governor rejected the bill and withheld his…….",option:{a:"accent",b:"assent",c:"access",d:"ascent"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:49,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:746,question:"The new school is not provided with .......for science practicals?",option:{a:"enough equipment",b:"equipments",c:"an equipment",d:"enough equipments"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"in this context, Option A is the best answer.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:50,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:747,question:"Much as I would love to visit him, I’m afraid ………",option:{a:"I won’t",b:"I can’t",c:" I can’t be able",d:"of visiting him"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:51,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:748,question:"llesa witness the largest ..... of writers at any convention in recent times?",option:{a:" turnaround",b:"turnover",c:"turn-out",d:"turn-on"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"Turn-out: go somewhere in order to attend a meeting, vote, play in a game, etc.",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:52,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:749,question:`The warring factions need words of…….
`,option:{a:"advise",b:"adverse",c:"advises",d:"advice"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:53,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:750,question:"The politicians were ....... by the press? ",option:{a:"marooned",b:"ridiculed",c:"eclipsed",d:"ostracized"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:54,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:751,question:"There are many……. to her personality.",option:{a:"moods",b:"styles",c:"facets",d:"faces"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:55,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:752,question:"There are several ........ in the farmyard?",option:{a:"sheep",b:"ewe",c:"lamb",d:"goat"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:56,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:753,question:"Audu fought with his ........ brother?",option:{a:"senior",b:"older",c:"bigger",d:"elder"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:57,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:754,question:"The Dark Continent was an ...... for Africa? ",option:{a:"abuse",b:"enigma",c:"eclectic",d:"epithet"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:58,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:755,question:"He arrived ....... to see his family leave for the countryside? ",option:{a:"in time",b:"timely",c:"late",d:"with"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:59,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:756,question:"You can travel on your own ......?",option:{a:" isn't it",b:"wouldn't you",c:"can't you",d:"shouldn't you"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:60,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:757,question:"Our culture does not allow one to ........ when an elderly person is speaking?",option:{a:"cut of",b:"cut off",c:"cut in",d:" cut on"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:61,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:758,question:"Raffle draws like gambling often end in a ....... for me?",option:{a:"lost",b:"loss",c:"loose",d:"lose"},section:"<b>In each of questions 41 to 62, fill the gap with the most appropriate option from the list provided.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:62,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:759,question:"If he were here, it could be more fun.",option:{a:"He did not show up and so the occasion lacked much fun",b:"He was being expected to supply more fun",c:"There was not fun because he was not present",d:"He was expected but did not show up to liven up the occasion"},section:`<b>In each of questions 63 to 67, select the option that best explain the information conveyed in the sentence?</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`If he were here, it could be more fun

This statement was referring to a third singular person. This means that, the event was fun. But the fun could have been more if that person was present.

''It could'' as used in the statement is a probability. There is no assurance that the presence of that particular person would bring more fun. 

Option A is the correct option. 

He did not show up and so the occasion lacked much fun
 Meaning there was fun, but it wasn't much fun because he wasn't present.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:63,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:760,question:"Though he is our elected representative he often takes a rather jaundiced view of our problems?",option:{a:" He takes a rather hazy view of our problems",b:"He takes an unfavourable position concerning our problems",c:"He takes a rather forceful view of our problems",d:"He takes a sickly view of our problems"},section:`<b>In each of questions 63 to 67, select the option that best explain the information conveyed in the sentence?</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:64,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:761,question:"When I visited James I only gave him a congratulatory card on account of his promotion?",option:{a:"The only person I visited was James and nobody else",b:"It was only James that I gave a congratulatory card to",c:"All I gave James when I visited him was a congratulatory card",d:"All I did when I visited James was given him a congratulatory card"},section:`<b>In each of questions 63 to 67, select the option that best explain the information conveyed in the sentence?</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:65,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:762,question:"The events of last Friday show that there is no love lost between the principal and the Vice-Principal? ",option:{a:"They like each other",b:"They work independently",c:"They cannot part company",d:"They dislike each other"},section:`<b>In each of questions 63 to 67, select the option that best explain the information conveyed in the sentence?</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:`No love lost between two people means that they are not friends, they dislike each other intensely.

If there is "no love lost" between two people, they have a strong hatred, hostility, or enmity for the other person, and make no attempt to conceal it.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:66,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:763,question:"The politician's inflammatory remarks were heavily criticized?",option:{a:"The politican's rude remarks were heavily criticized",b:"The politican's provocative remarks were heavily criticized",c:" The politician's bombastic remarks were heavily criticized",d:"The politician's tribalistic remarks were heavily criticized"},section:`<b>In each of questions 63 to 67, select the option that best explain the information conveyed in the sentence?</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:67,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:764,question:"The Governor told the chief that he was only on a <u>routine tour</u>?",option:{a:"normal and regular visit",b:"unplanned encounter",c:"surprise and imprompt check",d:" working visit and homage"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:68,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:765,question:"The boy was told that he would need <u>several</u> more pints of blood if he was to survive.",option:{a:"many",b:"much",c:"some",d:"plenty"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:69,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:766,question:"The principal told the teacher to stop <u>browbeating</u> the children? ",option:{a:"pampering",b:"bullying",c:"deceiving",d:"caning"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:70,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:767,question:"Some actions of the Nigerian youth have <u>alienated</u> them from those who were <u>sympathetic</u> to their cause?",option:{a:" endeared / kindly",b:"confronted / ill disposed",c:"separated / opposed",d:"estranged / well disposed"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:71,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:768,question:"The essay topic is <u>nebulous</u>?",option:{a:"vague",b:"incorrect",c:"distinct",d:"clear"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:72,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:769,question:"The man was able to persuade his <u>willful and obstinate</u> daughter to follow the career he chose for her?",option:{a:"intelligent but arrogant",b:"unyielding and obdurate",c:"secure and odious",d:"hardworking and intelligent"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:73,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:770,question:"Mr. Okon has been described as <u>an eagle-eyed editor</u>?. ",option:{a:"a short-sighted",b:"a clear-sighted",c:"a long-sighted",d:"a quick-sighted"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:74,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:771,question:"Inspite of her grim situation, the young widow smiled dutifully at the visitor's <u>pleasantries</u>?",option:{a:"unkind comments",b:"sad stories",c:"condolence messages",d:"jocular remarks"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:75,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:772,question:"I have always believed that my mother is a very <u>impassioned</u> woman?",option:{a:"emotion",b:"impartial",c:"impassive",d:"emotional"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:76,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:773,question:"The party gathering was thrown into a state of <u>euphoria</u> after the election result was announced?",option:{a:"pleasure",b:"sadness",c:"excitement",d:"confusion"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:77,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:774,question:"The family discussed the crime committed and resolved to <u>nail the lie to the counter</u>?",option:{a:"expose it publicly",b:"bury it in a coffin",c:"defer action on it",d:"seek more advice"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:78,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:775,question:"My father was at the <u>apogee</u> of his career when he was retired? ",option:{a:"terminal point",b:"highest point",c:"least productive stage",d:"redundant stage"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:79,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:776,question:"Though David's condition is <u>serious</u>, his life is not in immediate danger?",option:{a:" nastly",b:"hypertensive",c:"dangerous",d:"grave"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:80,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:777,question:"That punch by the young boxer prove to be <u>fatal</u>?",option:{a:"effective",b:"hard",c:"deadly",d:"belated"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`fatal; means causing death. 

Nearest in meaning is deadly.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:81,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:778,question:"The presence of the security men in the area will provide a <u>moment of respite</u> for the residents?",option:{a:"soothing relaxtion",b:"enduring reprieve",c:" lasting security",d:"tempoary relief"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:82,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:779,question:"It is time for all concerned to first <u>pick to pieces</u> the strike action before proffering solutions? ",option:{a:"embrace joyfully",b:"critically analyse",c:"stop abruptly",d:"commend highly"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:83,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:780,question:"The new ruler is <u>big-hearted</u> in his dealing with people?",option:{a:"generous",b:"cruel",c:"soft",d:"proud"},section:`<b>In each of questions 68 to 84, choose from the option nearest in meaning to the word underlined.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:84,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:781,question:"The teacher announced that the class would be making a <u>fleeting</u> visit to the zoo? ",option:{a:"routine",b:"brief",c:"long",d:"guided"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`fleeting lasting for a very short time.

long means having considerable or greater than usual duration in time. extending, lasting, or totaling a number of specified units: eight miles long; eight hours long. containing many items or units: a long list. requiring a considerable time to relate, read, etc.: a long story.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:85,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:782,question:"The project is designed to <u>alleviate</u> poverty in the country?",option:{a:"tackle",b:"exacerbate",c:"eradicate",d:"assuage"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:86,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:783,question:"Civil engineering is <u>predominantly</u> a male profession?",option:{a:"absolutely",b:"essentially",c:"generally",d:"seldom"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:87,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:784,question:"The officer said that he knew nothing to the <u>detriment</u> of the applicant?",option:{a:"damage",b:"disfavour",c:"advantage",d:"background"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:88,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:785,question:"When the driver applied the brakes, they <u>acted up</u>?",option:{a:"failed",b:"responded well",c:"were sluggish",d:"jammed"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:89,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:786,question:"The striking workers have vowed not to return to work until the decision is <u>rescinded</u>? ",option:{a:"changed",b:"dismissed",c:"implemented",d:"incorporated"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:90,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:787,question:"It is rare for a leader and his deputy to <u>see eye to eye</u>? ",option:{a:"disagree",b:"respect each other",c:"be of one mind",d:"reproach each other"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:91,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:788,question:"Common sense requires that one should be <u>decorous</u> at formal gatherings? ",option:{a:"courteous",b:"impolite",c:"incurious",d:"careful"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:92,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:789,question:"The diminutive figure bounces over the track with <u>unfathomable</u> lightness? ",option:{a:"invigorating",b:"irresistible",c:"predictable",d:"impressive"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:93,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:790,question:"I'm not interested in buying that shirt. I think it is <u>overpriced</u>?",option:{a:"too expensive",b:"overrated",c:"priceless",d:"cheap"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:94,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:791,question:"Despite his laxity in other matters, Ojo's father <u>drew the line</u> at truancy?",option:{a:"favoured",b:"rejected",c:"emphasized",d:"ignored"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:95,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:792,question:"The string was <u>taut</u>?",option:{a:"loose",b:"firm",c:"stretched",d:"tight"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:96,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:793,question:"Hypertension is a <u>debilitating</u> disease that everyone should prevent?",option:{a:"a mortal",b:"an enervating",c:" an energizing",d:"a horrible"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:97,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:794,question:"The permanent Secretary left his job under a <u>cloud</u>?",option:{a:"on a cloudy day",b:"with a clear record",c:"in disgrace",d:"on a sunny day"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:98,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:795,question:"We intend to make the reception a <u>diurnal</u> event?",option:{a:"a nightly",b:"a weekly",c:"a short",d:"an annual"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:99,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:796,question:"It is surprising that this politician has now turned <u>renegade</u>?",option:{a:"milliant",b:"corrupt",c:"loyal",d:"quiet"},section:`In each of questions 85 to 100, choose from the option <b>opposite</b> in meaning to the word underlined.
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000",questionNub:100,hasPassage:0,category:"others"}],n={subject:e,status:200,total:75,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,o as status,e as subject,a as total};
